Help on method popover in module streamlit.delta_generator:

popover(
    label: 'str',
    *,
    type: "Literal['primary', 'secondary', 'tertiary']" = 'secondary',
    help: 'str | None' = None,
    icon: 'str | None' = None,
    disabled: 'bool' = False,
    use_container_width: 'bool | None' = None,
    width: 'Width' = 'content'
) -> 'DeltaGenerator' method of streamlit.delta_generator.DeltaGenerator instance
    Insert a popover container.

    Inserts a multi-element container as a popover. It consists of a button-like
    element and a container that opens when the button is clicked.

    Opening and closing the popover will not trigger a rerun. Interacting
    with widgets inside of an open popover will rerun the app while keeping
    the popover open. Clicking outside of the popover will close it.

    To add elements to the returned container, you can use the "with"
    notation (preferred) or just call methods directly on the returned object.
    See examples below.

    .. note::
        To follow best design practices, don't nest popovers.

    Parameters
    ----------
    label : str
        The label of the button that opens the popover container.
        The label can optionally contain GitHub-flavored Markdown of the
        following types: Bold, Italics, Strikethroughs, Inline Code, Links,
        and Images. Images display like icons, with a max height equal to
        the font height.

        Unsupported Markdown elements are unwrapped so only their children
        (text contents) render. Display unsupported elements as literal
        characters by backslash-escaping them. E.g.,
        ``"1\. Not an ordered list"``.

        See the ``body`` parameter of |st.markdown|_ for additional,
        supported Markdown directives.

        .. |st.markdown| replace:: ``st.markdown``
        .. _st.markdown: https://docs.streamlit.io/develop/api-reference/text/st.markdown

    help : str or None
        A tooltip that gets displayed when the popover button is hovered
        over. If this is ``None`` (default), no tooltip is displayed.

        The tooltip can optionally contain GitHub-flavored Markdown,
        including the Markdown directives described in the ``body``
        parameter of ``st.markdown``.

    type : "primary", "secondary", or "tertiary"
        An optional string that specifies the button type. This can be one
        of the following:

        - ``"primary"``: The button's background is the app's primary color
          for additional emphasis.
        - ``"secondary"`` (default): The button's background coordinates
          with the app's background color for normal emphasis.
        - ``"tertiary"``: The button is plain text without a border or
          background for subtlety.

    icon : str
        An optional emoji or icon to display next to the button label. If ``icon``
        is ``None`` (default), no icon is displayed. If ``icon`` is a
        string, the following options are valid:

        - A single-character emoji. For example, you can set ``icon="\U0001f6a8"``
          or ``icon="\U0001f525"``. Emoji short codes are not supported.

        - An icon from the Material Symbols library (rounded style) in the
          format ``":material/icon_name:"`` where "icon_name" is the name
          of the icon in snake case.

          For example, ``icon=":material/thumb_up:"`` will display the
          Thumb Up icon. Find additional icons in the `Material Symbols \
          <https://fonts.google.com/icons?icon.set=Material+Symbols&icon.style=Rounded>`_
          font library.

        - ``"spinner"``: Displays a spinner as an icon.

    disabled : bool
        An optional boolean that disables the popover button if set to
        ``True``. The default is ``False``.

    use_container_width : bool
        Whether to expand the button's width to fill its parent container.
        If ``use_container_width`` is ``False`` (default), Streamlit sizes
        the button to fit its content. If ``use_container_width`` is
        ``True``, the width of the button matches its parent container.

        In both cases, if the content of the button is wider than the
        parent container, the content will line wrap.

        The popover container's minimum width matches the width of its
        button. The popover container may be wider than its button to fit
        the container's content.

        .. deprecated::
            ``use_container_width`` is deprecated and will be removed in a
            future release. For ``use_container_width=True``, use
            ``width="stretch"``. For ``use_container_width=False``, use
            ``width="content"``.

    width : int, "stretch", or "content"
        The width of the button. This can be one of the following:

        - ``"content"`` (default): The width of the button matches the
          width of its content, but doesn't exceed the width of the parent
          container.
        - ``"stretch"``: The width of the button matches the width of the
          parent container.
        - An integer specifying the width in pixels: The button has a
          fixed width. If the specified width is greater than the width of
          the parent container, the width of the button matches the width
          of the parent container.

        The popover container's minimum width matches the width of its
        button. The popover container may be wider than its button to fit
        the container's contents.

    Examples
    --------
    You can use the ``with`` notation to insert any element into a popover:

    >>> import streamlit as st
    >>>
    >>> with st.popover("Open popover"):
    >>>     st.markdown("Hello World \U0001f44b")
    >>>     name = st.text_input("What's your name?")
    >>>
    >>> st.write("Your name:", name)

    .. output::
        https://doc-popover.streamlit.app/
        height: 400px

    Or you can just call methods directly on the returned objects:

    >>> import streamlit as st
    >>>
    >>> popover = st.popover("Filter items")
    >>> red = popover.checkbox("Show red items.", True)
    >>> blue = popover.checkbox("Show blue items.", True)
    >>>
    >>> if red:
    ...     st.write(":red[This is a red item.]")
    >>> if blue:
    ...     st.write(":blue[This is a blue item.]")

    .. output::
        https://doc-popover2.streamlit.app/
        height: 400px

